RG 108, Arts and Crafts Club of Hartford
Connecticut State Library
Arts and Crafts Club of Hartford records
1909-1951
Connecticut State Library
Arts and Crafts Club of Hartford
0.5 cubic feet
The Club was organized prior to 1909 with the purpose “to associate those actively or otherwise interested in the various branches of the arts and crafts for mutual benefit; to foster and promote interest in the handicrafts... and to encourage and stimulate... wider participation in and appreciation of good craftwork in all its branches.”
RG108
T001444
Historical Note
The Club was organized prior to 1909 with the purpose “to associate those actively or otherwise interested in the various branches of the arts and crafts for mutual benefit; to foster and promote interest in the handicrafts... and to encourage and stimulate... wider participation in and appreciation of good craftwork in all its branches.” The club maintained a workshop, sponsored and organized exhibits, demonstrations, lectures and study courses and held periodic meetings. When the interest of the members waned, the Club was legally terminated in 1951, with its material assets divided among the Children’s Museum, the West Hartford Art League, and the Society of Connecticut Craftsmen.
Scope and Content
Records include minutes of meetings, correspondence, reports of officers, the Club Constitution, and membership lists.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Arts and Crafts Club of Hartford
Subjects:
Art -- Societies, etc.; Clubs -- Connecticut -- Hartford; Arts and Crafts Club of Hartford -- Records and correspondence; Women -- Connecticut -- Hartford -- Societies and clubs
Document Types:
Minutes; Reports; Membership lists; Correspondence
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
In October 1952, the last President Mrs. J. L. Prentis, donated the records to the Library.
Container List
- Records, 1909-1951
  - 1. Minutes of meetings, 1909-1951; 3 volumes + 4 binders (Box 1)
    Includes some correspondence, reports of officers, the Club Constitution, membership lists, etc.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1909-1914 May, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1914 June-1922, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1923-1930, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1930-1935, 1 binder (Box 1)
    - 1936-1938, 1 binder (Box 1)
    - 1939-1941, 1 binder (Box 1)
    - 1942-1951, 1 binder (Box 1)
  - 2. Membership lists, circa 1939-1940; 1 notebook (Box 1)
  - 3. Programs, 1935-1941; 6 pamphlets (Box 1)
    Includes membership lists.
  - 4. List of artists and craftsmen, undated; 1 pamphlet (Box 1)